Ahmed Mandalawi

Toronto, ON M6R

Email: al.mandalawi@mail.utoronto.ca Website: www.mandalawi.ca



Cell: (647)784.8222

In: linkedin.com/in/ahmedalmandalawi

GitHub: github.com/mandalaw

EDUCATION

Honours in Bachelor of Science (Computer Science and GIS)

University of Toronto - 2022

QUALIFICATION

Languages: Java, Python, HTML5,6, CSS, JavaScript (ES6+), C, C++, Bash, MongoDB, GraphQL, JSON, XML, MySQL, R

Tools: Git, GitHub, Jira, VScode, PyCharm, Eclipse, IntelliJ, Slack, MySQL, UML, Adobe Suites, Adobe XD, Figma, Prismic.

Frameworks/Libraries: NodeJS, ReactJS, VueJS, Redux, VueX, jQuery, Bootstrap, Vuetify, Styled Components, GatsbyJS, NextJS, NuxtJS, ExoressJS, SciPy, NumPy, Pandas.

TECHNICAL SKILLS (LANGUAGES | TOOLS | FRAMEWORKS/LIBRARIES)



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A University of Toronto graduate with an Honours Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Geographic Information System (GIS), advanced coding skills, strong written and oral communication, self-motivation, and a desire to advance professionally. Years of professional Software Engineering experience in both back-end and front-end. I am passionate about full-stack web development, AWS services, cloud infrastructures, and user experience design. I have experience working in and leading teams in an agile environment and building new SaaS platforms.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

GDSC (Google Developer Student Club)

Jan 2022- April 2022

Stack Developer

- Designed and developed user websites using React, Node JS, Express and Mongo DB. Provided up-to-date modern
 website designs with dark mode functionality.
- Worked in an agile team setting and saw the project from conception to finished product.
- Designed and developed APIs while meeting both technical and consumer needs.
- Completed multiple iterations and redesigned the entire site structure, navigation, and interactivity using Figma to accomplish website objectives
- Spent time arranging product backlog and setting estimates to ensure efficient sprints. Decided on efficiency and improvement for the code.
- Established standard process for code development and migration within development, staging, and production environments for a consistent methodology
- Set communication guidelines for sprint meetings to ensure code quality and receive mentoring from senior developers.
- Designed, developed, and implemented core features including a custom booking system, and an admin panel.
- Used a JWT-based authentication system for user accounts
- Designed and developed APIs while meeting both technical and consumer needs.
- Created CRC cards, schedules, system design, UML classes, GitHub readme, Jira backlog, and burndown charts for each sprint.
- Started sprints by updating product backlog and criteria of satisfaction for each task
- Ended sprints by updating our system design, UML classes, and GitHub readme

City of Mississauga

Sept 2021- Feb 2022

GIS Analyst

 Worked closely with city mentors and team members to meet project goals, requirements, and desired timelines using Waterfall & Agile Methodology

- With less than 3% space within the city, the goal of the project was to find suitable spaces in the City of Mississauga
 that can be transformed into community gardens.
- Data manipulation and advanced mapping automation using model builder through python code (ArcPy)
- Used statistics, open-source data, and research to discover patterns and trends with the help of spatial mapping software to create a finalized recommended location that met the criteria for the city.
- Responsible for maintaining and testing web functionality. Updated code, content, and fixed bugs from support tickets via Microsoft Teams.

Routeability

Jan 2021- August 2021

Junior software developer

- Mobility through data that maps urban pedestrian infrastructures in a comprehensive, accurate and reliable way.
 Leverages leading-edge technology to efficiently capture and map the current state of urban pedestrian infrastructures and develop a pedestrian route that enables all levels of mobility.
- Developed, tested, and maintained several web and desktop-based business applications.
- Prepared reports and manuals on the status, operation, and maintenance of software.
- Analyzed and resolved technical application problems and provided third-level support to business users.
- Worked with teammates in the migration of applications to current Microsoft technologies.
- Created portal for collectively gather and share spatial data to improve accessibility.

SGS Canada

October 2019- Sept 2021

Transportation and Logistics Operations

- Commercial Vehicle tracking uses software to monitor and manage a fleet of vehicles. Collecting storing coordinate
 data and displaying it using Google API.
- Collect data on location and vehicle health, as well as driving behaviour and fleet productivity.
- Adhering to assigned routes and following time schedules.
- In direct contact with clients and colleagues. Review orders before and after delivery to ensure that orders are complete, the charges are correct, and the client is satisfied.

Uber, Toronto (Toronto Head Office Greenhub)

May 2015- February 2018

PSR (Partner Support Representative) & Driver Strategy, Canada Rides

- Communicate with customers and drivers by providing detailed instructions to resolve driver challenges.
- Using the Uber platform to offer additional modes of transportation to get customers from A to B.
- Independently handled and organized office operations and procedures.
- Respond to internal and external requests for information. Worked with product and marketing teams.
- Created reports, made schedules, corresponded and spreadsheets with great accuracy.
- Work closely with other representatives and assist the head manager with several large-scale projects.

University of Toronto

March 2018- August 2018

GIS and Multimedia Student Assistant

- Digital mapping and geospatial creation and editing
- Organizing of paper maps and digital data holdings
- ArcGIS Pro tutorial video creation including editing and uploading
- Providing reference referrals to appropriate staff
- Gathering, entering, and analyzing data, including manipulating data and cleaning up data sources.
- Mapping is used to provide general assistance to students, staff, and faculty in technical support at the University of Toronto.

PROJECTS

Freelance Web Development

Sept 2019 - Current

- Created various Personal and Freelance businesses operated websites using MERN Stack application from scratch. The
 goals of these projects were to attain further knowledge on how to use frameworks and concepts such as React,
 Express, React hooks, Routes, Authentication, and MongoDB database. Developed, tested, and maintained several
 web and desktop-based business applications.
- Used a JWT-based authentication system for user accounts.
- Utilized React Hooks to manage States and Props.
- Increased code efficiency by utilizing reusable Components.
- Replicated GDSC-like interface- created user profiles, following and follower system, create/delete posts, like and comment on posts.

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Drone operations

- Able to fly drones for the purposes of data collection.
- Thorough understanding of Canada Flight Supplement and Designated Airspace Handbook.
- Able to manipulate, address and interpret aerial data using Remote sensing software.
- Providing accuracy assessments in compliance with RMSE.
- Active backcountry camping and backpacking

References available upon request